Hi I'm Prof Navarro.
مرحباً أنا البروفيسور نافارو
>> And I'm Alex LeBon.
>> وأنا أليس ليبون.
>> So Mister Alex, what are we gonna do here in our final lesson?
>> إذن يا سيد اليكس، ماذا سنفعل هنا في درسنا الأخير؟
It better be epic.
من الأفضل أن تكون ملحمية
>> Well I'm not sure I can deliver on that.
>> حسنا أنا لست متأكدا من أنني يمكن أن يسلم على ذلك.
But I am going to take you on a roller coaster ride through what
لكنني سآخذك على متن السفينة الدوارة من خلال ما
the best MBAs know.
يعرفه أفضل ماجستير في إدارة الأعمال.
>> The best MBAs know.
>> أفضل ماجيستير في إدارة الأعمال تعرف.
That sounds pretty ambitious.
هذا يبدو طموحاً جداً
>> True.
>> صحيح.
But whether you are going to go into business for yourself or
ولكن سواء كنت ستذهب إلى العمل بنفسك أو
simply need some skills for your own personal financial needs, I can't think
تحتاج ببساطة إلى بعض المهارات لتلبية احتياجاتك المالية الشخصية، لا أستطيع التفكير
of a better way of obtaining those skills than by stealing from the MBA playbook.
في طريقة أفضل للحصول على هذه المهارات من السرقة من كتاب ماجستير إدارة الأعمال.
>> All right Mr. Sticky Fingers, so are we ready to start?
>> كل الحق السيد أصابع لزجة، لذلك نحن على استعداد للبدء؟
>> Not quite. I want to challenge you to a quotation
>> ليس تماما. أريد أن أتحداك في
contest.
مسابقة الاقتباس
>> All right, what are the rules?
>> كل الحق، ما هي القواعد؟
We'll take turns naming a functional area of the MBA curriculum, and
سنتناوب على تسمية مجال وظيفي من منهج ماجستير إدارة الأعمال،
the other person has to come up with a cool quote.
والشخص الآخر يجب أن يأتي مع اقتباس بارد.
>> Hm. Sounds like fun.
>> جلالة يبدو ممتعا
You go first.
انت اذهبي اولا
>> Right.
>> الحق.
Here's an easy one.
هنا واحد سهل.
Marketing. >> Marketing.
التسويق. >> التسويق.
All right, how about this?
حسناً، ماذا عن هذا؟
People don't buy quarter-inch drills, they buy quarter-inch holes.
الناس لا يشترون تدريبات ربع بوصة، بل يشترون ثقوب ربع بوصة.
>> Not bad. How about one more from marketing?
>> ليس سيئا. ماذا عن واحد آخر من التسويق؟
>> All right, hm.
>> حَسَناً، hm.
All right, here we go.
حسناً، ها نحن ذا
In the factory we make cosmetics, at the drugstore we sell hope.
في المصنع نصنع مستحضرات التجميل، في الصيدلية نبيع الأمل.
>> Nice.
>> لطيف.
>> Now, your turn.
>> الآن، دورك
Here's your category.
ها هي فئتك
Statistics.
الإحصاءات.
>> Here's my favorite.
>> ها هي المفضلة لدي.
You can't manage what you can't measure.
لا يمكنك إدارة ما لا يمكنك قياسه
>> Hm. That's pretty good.
>> جلالة هذا جيد جداً
Got another one from statistics?
حصلت على واحدة أخرى من الإحصائيات؟
>> Heck no, statisticians are boring.
>> هيك لا، الإحصائيين مملة.
And on the subject of boring, how about a quotation from accounting?
وحول موضوع مملة، ماذا عن اقتباس من المحاسبة؟
All right.
حسناً
How about this,
ماذا عن هذا،
the earlier you get the information, the easier it is to fix the problem.
في وقت سابق تحصل على المعلومات، وأسهل هو لإصلاح المشكلة.
>> Well done, since I'm not likely to stump you,
>> أحسنت، بما أنني لست من المحتمل أن أجذعك،
how about we get on with this lesson?
فماذا عن المضي في هذا الدرس؟
>> [LAUGH] Okay, ready when you are.
>> [ضحك] حسنا، على استعداد عندما كنت.
[MUSIC]
[ موسيقى]